<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tristianazuara</title><link>tristian.us/</link><description></description><atom:link href="tristian.us/feeds/tristian-azuara.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><item><title>Git Commands</title><link>tristian.us/git-commands.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you use git as your version control tool and have ever needed to use it in
an unusual way here I will list uses that took me more than 10 mins of reading
until I found a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're new to git here is an excelent resource: &lt;a href="http://www.git-scm.com/"&gt;http://www.git-scm.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Last commit message text&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;git log | grep &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;^\s\s*&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; | head -n1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tristian Azuara</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:,2014-08-07:tristian.us/git-commands.html</guid><category>git</category><category>bash</category><category>cli</category></item><item><title>Personal Site (tristian.us)</title><link>tristian.us/personal-site.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Like every professional in the software and engineering industry I needed a way to convey
my knowledge, experience and skills to future clients; in other words to create a personal brand. 
Thats how the planning and development of this site began.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Constraints, Goals and oportunities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One cannot just decide that you need a personal site and get started with the development. As with every project it has to be 
planned; to a certain degree (not to every detail).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had simple goals for this site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It had to reflect my skills, knowledge and experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It had to function as a publishing platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It had to provide a way to engage prospects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It had to have a clean, simple and maintaineble design (visually and logically).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above goals are quite common, simple and a bit vague. Thats why every project (and system) 
needs to adhere to &lt;em&gt;constraints&lt;/em&gt; that allow to narrow down the paths on how to reach
the stablished goals. Constraints can be of any type; technical, technological or resourced based are few of 
the most common types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The constraints for this project were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It had to be a &lt;em&gt;static&lt;/em&gt; generated site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It had to use free hosting platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It had to strive for web responsiveness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It had to rely on FOSS components.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It had to be easy to maintain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The constraints pretty much limit the &lt;em&gt;solution space&lt;/em&gt;, my constraints were mostly technical and technology 
focused because a personal site is an on-going project in which time is not rigourously controlled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion every project that is undertaken should offer oportunities of growth and self-improvement; be it
by learning new skills, trying new technologies or adopting different methodologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design not only refers to the visual design but also on how the solution will be aproached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second goal "reflect my skills, knwoledge and experience" obviously requires an about page (about me)
where I list my areas of expertise and how I've developed my self profesionally and technically. 
I had an objective for my about page; It had to use charts to represent my knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third goal defines it as a &lt;em&gt;publishing&lt;/em&gt; platform; that involves having content produced peridically.
Content would be related to the work and services that I offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth goal is to engage prospects. My solution to that offer a newsletter/mailing list where 
visitors can subscribe and receive updates with content that add value to their business or that are
relevant to their fields. Also a comments section for each publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fifth goal says that it has to be maintainable, be simple and clean. This particular goal 
requires use of creativity and is polished across all stages of the project, it was not decided
completely at the start of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Implementation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, now that I've defined in terms of the user experience how the site will work it is time to determine
the tools and technology to implement it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the creation of a personal site, I wanted to explore using a static site genertor, also I wanted it 
to be python based. That left me with only two options (that I know of):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://hyde.github.io/"&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I tried using Hyde, but it seems like the project development has not been that active and I had 
a few issues while testing it. Then I tried pelican and I was convinced, it seemed to fit my work flow better
and I like the way it has been architected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For showing my skills I wanted to use a chart, after fiddling with the idea of creating a charting library specific for showing skills
I found &lt;a href="http://www.chartjs.org/"&gt;chart.js&lt;/a&gt; which is an absolutly wonderfull charting library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then started looking on how to create themes for Pelican something that is well documented on the &lt;a href="http://pelican.readthedocs.org/en/latest/themes.html"&gt;Pelican docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The articles are created using markdown, reStructured text or even html if a more &lt;em&gt;intricate&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;detailed&lt;/em&gt; article is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To showcase projects that I've worked on I'll create articles and categorize them with the &lt;code&gt;project&lt;/code&gt; category, those articles 
will not appear on the index page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a personal site is like every project, it has to be planned, it has to be contrained and it 
has to offer oportunities of personal and professional growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is an ongoing project but I believe I've set the guidelines and took advantage of the oportunities it presented.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tristian Azuara</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:,2014-08-01:tristian.us/personal-site.html</guid><category>personal-site</category><category>planning</category></item><item><title>Mobile Foreign Rate Exchange</title><link>tristian.us/mwfx.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Indonesia based design firm needed for their mobile app designs to be implemented.
The application allowed for it's users to track rate exchange pairs and see how the prices (bid, ask, 
high and low) have changed at different time resolutions (seconds, minutes, hours and days).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pricing information was obtained from Megawastu's propietary api.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why I worked on this project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having worked as a frontend developer I had the experience and skills to create a solution that would be 
cross platform, usable and consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What problems got solved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having to manually check trading prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having to manually summarize price deltas accross different timespans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Efforts to develop for different platforms were reduced by using a hybrid app development approach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An app was delivered within 60 days, meeting design requirements, functional requirements and several improvements to the 
API were suggested to improve integration with mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tristian Azuara</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:,2014-02-20:tristian.us/mwfx.html</guid><category>Javascript</category><category>HTML</category><category>CSS</category><category>LESS</category><category>Angular.js</category><category>Foundation</category><category>single-page-application</category><category>frontend</category><category>mobile</category><category>apache-cordova</category><category>android</category><category>blackberry10</category><category>ios</category></item><item><title>Translation and Theme Customisation</title><link>tristian.us/progressfin.com.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A San Francisco based company needed to complete the spanish version of their site; which 
mainly served the hispanic community. It also needed to add a news and events section, 
with the ability to manage the publishing of news and events posts from the admin panel of the wordpress installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why I worked on this project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having worked with the front end team to develop the company's main product platform. I had the skills 
and cultural knowledge to complete the spanish version of the site and to implement the news and events page in
an intuitive manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What problems got solved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site's spanish version was now available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many grammatical errors on the spanish version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wording of the translations; a proper use of "slang" words relevant to their customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uniformity in presenting success stories of customers and the company's team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improved code base where possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the site available in the primary language of its customers reinforced the company's commitment 
to serving the hispanic community in helping them succeed and on creating a positive credit score. Also, it improved
the communication of the company's mission by using a more familiar tone and wording in spanish (a bit less formal).&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tristian Azuara</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:,2013-10-10:tristian.us/progressfin.com.html</guid><category>PHP</category><category>Wordpress</category><category>web-application</category><category>i18n</category><category>HTML</category><category>CSS</category><category>Javascript</category></item><item><title>Loan Application and Disbursement</title><link>tristian.us/lad.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A San Francisco based company needed to expand their bandwidth to keep moving forward the development
of the project that enabled the company's flagship product; &lt;em&gt;responsible loans&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why I worked on this project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the knowledge, experience and skills to provide additional man-power that would help increase the usability and quality of the product. Also, I was a good fit with the
team and company culture; based on their customer profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What problems got solved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most significant were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missing cross-browser functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User Interface consistency accross browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big and small errors in the code base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repeated code fragments that were re-factored into reusable modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improved semantics of HTML and CSS that allowed for easier Selenium tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company decreased iteration times on the platform that allowed its flagship product to be offered.
It refined the platform and ease the loan application and disbursement process when
performed by the agent.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tristian Azuara</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:,2013-08-01:tristian.us/lad.html</guid><category>Javascript</category><category>HTML</category><category>CSS</category><category>LESS</category><category>Backbone.js</category><category>Bootstrap3</category><category>single-page-application</category><category>frontend</category></item><item><title>Enterprise Resource Planning</title><link>tristian.us/erp-tryton-core.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company was looking into transitioning its systems to use a Enterprise Resource Planning
system. The system would be deployed in phases, as a starting point a production (manufactoring)
reporting module will be created, followed with a Human Resources and Inventory module that supported
assembly and line provisioning operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why I worked in this project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had already worked with them in creating several web applications that bridged legacy systems with the new
web applications, I've also had created an API that exposed the information contained in the legacy systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the experience and knowledge to search for an ERP system or framework that suited their budget and 
deadlines given their actual infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Problems that were solved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Production engineers no longer had to ask for WRITTEN production reports, it was all calculated 
   automatically by the ERP system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would now be traces of which work shift manager captured and verified the production count.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data was now archived in a proper database system, queryable and auditible instead of being 
   scattered in Excel Spreadsheets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data was now accessible any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inventory levels were now automatically calculated and initiated by employees rather than by the purchasing 
   department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was now possible to usage activity in the ERP system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Production reports were now available immediately after the data had been captured by the work shift manager, this
allowed for production managers to analyse the data, inform their superiors, make forecast and decisions in a much
more timely manner that beneffited the company in keep their customers happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also since everything was logged the system provided accountability for actions during each shift. It also foster
a culture of transparence within production managers and production engineers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tristian Azuara</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:,2012-04-03:tristian.us/erp-tryton-core.html</guid><category>Python</category><category>Enterprise</category><category>application-server</category><category>TrytonERP</category><category>matplotlib</category></item><item><title>Online Order Processing (Inherited)</title><link>tristian.us/coom.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A company merger was in place and both companies had similiar technlogies due to being in the same market.
I had to find a way to take advantage of the tech assets that the merge would bring in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why I worked in this project.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was the right person for this project because I had built a similar web application for one of the 
merging companies, thus I would be really familiar with the domain knowledge of the inherited application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What problems got solved.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most significant were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employees (customer service) workflow was greatly simplified because now they had access to the data in ONE
   application instead of requiring to log onto two different applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data was centralized and it no longer had to be updated in two different places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customer was now able to check the status of its order (a product that had to be manufactured and that took 1 to 3 weeks to complete)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customer was able to place their orders online, at any time (product highly configurable)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This allowed for the CEO to onboard new customers by leverging the company's tech offering of visibility and 
self-service. It also simplified customer service and production engineers workflow because data was now availble
in a digital format and could be placed into production much more easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It impacted revenue and operation costs in a positive way.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tristian Azuara</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:,2012-01-01:tristian.us/coom.html</guid><category>php</category><category>css</category><category>html</category><category>javascript</category><category>jquery</category><category>mysql</category><category>web-application</category></item><item><title>Warranty Management</title><link>tristian.us/warranty-management.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A faulty batch of 100+ products that was already shipped to the customers was discovered, because
of that it was expected that many orders were to be re-manufactured a systemized approach 
was planned to avoid interrupting the workflow of new orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why I worked in this project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had already worked with this company in developing their online order entry systems, which integrated 
with their manufacturing software. I had the knowledge about their product and the skills needed
to provide them with the warranty platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What problems got solved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No more duplicate warranties, because the original claimed warranty was now trackable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remove the hassle for the customer of claiming a warranty, the process was now completly web-driven
   without the need to call customer service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unability to track the warranted order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remove the difficulty of determing if the warranty was applicable or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The need to retype the order into the manufacturing system, the re-make order integrated witht the
   manufacturing software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reduced operation costs in fulfilling the warranties. Reduced false-positive warranty cases. 
Improved the company's image because it proved that the company would take responsability of 
it's mistakes and reimburse the customer or provide a remake for the same order.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tristian Azuara</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:,2012-01-01:tristian.us/warranty-management.html</guid><category>java</category><category>servlets</category><category>tomcat</category><category>mysql</category><category>web-application</category><category>html</category><category>css</category><category>javascript</category></item><item><title>Online Order Processing</title><link>tristian.us/tubsdb.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company needed to digitize itself; eliminating paper work and easing the job 
burden of customer service by automating certain steps of the order fulfillment 
process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why I worked in this project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first project in a professional environment. I had the skills needed to complete the project.
In a way it was a risk that the customer took but the outcome was much greater that the actual risk, and 
in the end everyone was happy with the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What problems got solved&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most siginificant were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Orders could be placed online, at anytime, from anywhere. Customer Service would review them 
   and place them into production each morning; if the order was correct and complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Order traces and logs stopped getting lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logs of interaction between the customer and customer service were created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrated with the manufacturing system, and avoided data duplication when placing the orders
   into the production line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Created a new tech asset for the company, which would bring &lt;strong&gt;many future&lt;/strong&gt; customers. Reduced operation costs
by simplifying customer service duties. Reduced manufacturing errors by removing the need to retype the order 
into the manufacturing system. Improved the companies image because it was now one of the few with IT automation
systems within the industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tristian Azuara</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:,2010-08-20:tristian.us/tubsdb.html</guid><category>java</category><category>servlets</category><category>tomcat</category><category>css</category><category>html</category><category>web-application</category><category>javascript</category><category>mysql</category></item></channel></rss>